# atricio López Juri

Santiago, Chile

🛘 (+56) 990511003 | 💌 patricio@lopezjuri.com | 🌴 https://lopezjuri.com | 🖸 lopezjurip | 🛅 lopezjuri | 💆 @lopezjuri

## Summary\_

Born to create software for humans. Industrial Civil Engineer with 5+ years of experience building and coding with additional knowledge in design and finance. Specialized in architecture, infrastructure, web & mobile development, blockchain and a thing or two in machine learning. Expert in React.js, Node.js, Ruby and Python. Some experience with Swift, Java, Kotlin, C#, C, and Go.

Digital nomad (+20 countries working remotely and still counting), foodie, vintage vinyl record collector and music nerd.

## Work Experience \_

ConsenSys.net Remote & Brooklyn, NY, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2019 - PRESENT

- Architect of the TokenFoundry.com platform that was able to raise more than US\$30 million total from the sales of Virtue Poker and FOAM tokens during 2018 in a legal and secure manner.
- Successfully integrated KYC (Know Your Costumer) services into the platform to prevent money laundry and blacklist politically exposed users.
- Implemented a quiz system to prevent speculators from purchasing tokens.
- Built component library using React.js + styled-components and successfully implemented server-side rendering.
- · Built software and systems that integrated with the Ethereum blockchain on the frontend and on the backend.
- Worked customizing pip modules related to OAuth2 and its integration with Django 2.
- Implemented GraphQL in a microservice-based architecture for DaisyPayments.com.

## **Pontifical Catholic University of Chile - Postgraduate School**

Santiago, Chile

ADJUNCT INSTRUCTOR PROFESSOR

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Imparting course: Technologies and Applications of the World Wide Web to 10 professional students.
- Designed from scratch a course with hands-on methodology using Ruby on Rails.
- · Lessons about HTTP, business models and basics of web design.
- Recorded programming session about Ruby on Rails, HTML and CSS for the classroom.

#### ImpulsoDocente (Foundation)

Santiago, Chile

SOLO FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun. 2017 - Nov. 2017

- Design and implementation a mobile to help teachers improve their methodology through videos and feedback.
- Built with React-Native, Redux and Ruby on Rails.
- Addressed UI/UX concepts and taught product-management methods (Kanban) to clients.

## FEUC (Federación de Estudiantes de la Universidad Católica de Chile)

Santiago, Chile

SOLO FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- · Lead the requirement gathering, design and implementation of a mobile app built with React-Native and Redux with a Express.js, Keystone.js and MongoDB backend.
- Available at https://github.com/open-source-uc/FEUC-mobile and got arround 5000 downloads (iOS & Android).

#### **Pontifical Catholic University of Chile**

Santiago, Chile Aug. 2013 - Dec 2017

TEACHING ASSISTANT (EACH CLASS WITH AROUND 30 STUDENTS)

- · Mentor for the Major Field Capstone Project guides a team of to 10 last-year computer science students during the full development cycle of a software project: 2 semesters.
- Software System Architecture: 1 semester.
- Detailed Software Design: 1 semester.
- Advanced Design of Web Applications: 1 semester.
- Software Engineering: 1 semester.

EGGHEAD INSTRUCTOR

- Web Technologies and Applications: 2 semesters.
- · Advanced Programming: 5 semesters.

Booz cl Santiago, Chile

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2017 - May. 2017

Mar. 2017 - PRESENT

• Implement shopping cart and a search feature with Node.js, MongoDB and jQuery.

· Code refactoring caused several improvements such as increased overall speed and reduced client-side files size.

egghead.io Remote

· Prepare, record and edit an online video course about developing modern JSON WEB APIs with Koa and the latest JavaScript semantics. (Work in progress).

AUGUST 4, 2019 LOPEZJURI.COM Mediastream SpA Santiago, Chile

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2016 - Feb 2017

• Research about Functions as a Service (FaaS) and evaluate the project of splitting the main monolithic service from Express.js and MongoDB to AWS Lambda and DynamoDB.

- Lead developer at the design and implementation a full-stack application with Koa, Amazon RDS, React, React-Native and Redux with shared code-base and i18n support.
- · Prepare and evaluate technical interviews for senior candidates.
- Improve developers experience by setting a developer-friendly and debuggable environment.

#### Núcleo Milenio Centro de Investigación de la Web Semántica - CIWS

Santiago, Chile Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2017

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Lead developer in charge of updating the official website to a new CMS in Node.js and MongoDB from Python and MySQL.

## **Honors & Awards**

2017	Participant, Facebook International Hackathon 2017	California, USA
2017	1st Place, Facebook Chile Regional Hackathon 2017	Santiago, Chile
2017	Honor, Outstanding Student (Engineering at Pontifical Catholic University of Chile)	Santiago, Chile
2014	2nd Place, Start-up Weekend Chile	Santiago, Chile
2014	Best Social App, ChileHack	Santiago, Chile

## **Presentation**

Blockchain Latam Submit CDMX, México

SPEAKER REPRESENTING DAISYPAYMENTS.COM (CONSENSYS)

Jul. 2019

 Introduced DaisyPayments project and talked about the different implementations of subscription-based projects using the Ethereum blockchain.

### **Blockchain Submit Uruguay**

Montevideo, Uruquay

TECHNICAL SPEAKER AT BLOCKCHAIN WORKSHOP

Sept. 2018

• Ethereum workshop: introduction to Web3 with Metamask, Ganache and Solidity.

## Writing.

## Anatomicis Network: A Cloud-based Educational Software Platform to Enhance Anatomy Teaching in Medical Education

Journal ISI

RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT

Jan. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- Product manager and lead developer of a group of 10 last-year computer science student.
- Requirement gathering, design and implementation of a cloud-based teaching and learning platform with live editing, quizzes and 3D medical
  anatomical models.

#### **Advanced Programming in Python**

CONICYT Founded Project

BOOK WRITER

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2016

- Participant in the writing of a book about advanced programming concepts and usage in Python. Wrote about Webservices and Networking.
- Translate other content and code from Spanish to English.

## **Education**

#### **Pontifical Catholic University of Chile**

Santiago, Chile

CIVIL INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER, COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Mar. 2012 - Dec. 2017

- · Led open-source organization for student-developed software. See https://github.com/open-source-uc.
- Local ACM group participant, designer and community manager.
- Recognized teaching assistant.

## Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

Alma Máter UC

Santiago, Chile

EMBER Jan. 2014 - Jan. 2016

• Design and development of a mobile app for iOS and Android (Objc & Java). It had over 30.000 downloads. It was a free mobile app for the students of the Pontifical Catholic University of Chile (unofficial)